American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 6, 1896; 9x5-3/4, 4-3/4x5-3/4, 8-1/2x5-1/2; Eickhoff & Kraemer
    Phila., L. 1p. 2 Ms. notes pasted to sheet Bookbinding estimates. Refers to J.F. Sachse.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Nov. 6, 1896; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns W.C. Taylor's application for work in the library.
  - Letter tothe American philosophical society, Nov. 6, 1896; 10-1/2x8; Stockhausen, P. C.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Gives estimate for printing half-tones.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 9, 1896; 8x5; Sulzberger, Mayer, 1843-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will prepare obituary of J.B. Townsend.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 10, 1896; 8-3/4x5-1/2, 9-1/4x5-3/4; Haeckel, Ernst, 1834-1919
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. of 2p. printed letter Exchange of publications. Sends form letter of thanks.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 10, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; James, Joseph Francis, 1857-1897
    Hingham, Mass., A.L.S. 4p. Offers paper on scientific work of his father, T.P. James. Refers to A. Hyatt.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 10, 1896; 9x5-1/2; Lackawanna institute of history and science, Scranton, Pa.
    Scranton, Pa., A.L.S.: Charles LeRoy Wheeler, Curator and Librarian 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter asking for subscriptions, Nov. 20, 1896; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society, Thoms Henry Huxley memorial fund
    Phila., Typed L. 1p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 20, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p., end. Asks permission to examine MS. journal of Thomas Sullivan, with eye to future publication. Refers to F.P. Harper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 20, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 23, 1896; 10x8; Ludlow, William, 1843-1901
    Tompkinsville, N.Y., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Nov. 24, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns the Thomas Sullivan journal of the Revolution. Refers to Phillips.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 24, 1896; 5-1/2x8-1/2; W.H. Lowdermilk & Co.
    Washington, Typed L. 1p., end. Orders Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 24, 1896; 10-1/2x8; Stockhausen, P. C.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns estimate for printing halftones.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 1, 1896; 11x8-1/2, 10-1/2x8, 9x8; International subscription for the Pasteur monument
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. 3 encs. Sends announcement, subscription form and return envelope.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 3, 1896; 8x5; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about copy of Memoirs of the Columbian Chemical Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 5, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hickcox, John H.
    Washington, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about book by A.L. Holley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 7, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Dixon, Samuel Gibson, 1851-1918
    [Phila.,]. L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, Dec. 9, 1896; 11x8-1/2; Barber, Edwin Atlee, 1851-1916
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Letter of resignation.
  - Letter to George F[rederick] Barker, Dec. 10, 1896; 10x8; Clark, Arthur Hamilton, 1841-1922
    Cleveland, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Requests copies of A.P.S. rules and membership list.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Dec. 12, 1896; 5-1/2x4-3/4; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p., end. by Frazer Submits paper for publication.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, Dec. 17, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for list of appropriations by Finance Committee for 1888-1890.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 17, 1896; 9-3/4x6-1/2; University of Pennsylvania Wistar institute of anatomy and biology
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Horace [Fort] Jayne 2p., end. Acknowledges gift.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 19, 1896; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Rawson, Rawson William, Sir, 1812-1899
    London, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends photograph.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Dec. 22, 1896; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Phillips prize circular. Refers to R. Vaux. Requests Horn's list of members attending in 1896.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Dec. 23, 1896; 8x4-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Washington], A.L.S. 2p. Accepts appointment to represent A.P.S. at memorial meeting for G.B. Goode. Refers to Brinton, Gill.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Dec. 24, 1896; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Accepts appointment as A.P.S. representative at memorial meeting for G.B. Goode.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 24, 1896; 11x8-1/4; Mattice, Asa E.
    Albion, Mich., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks how to become a member.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Dec. 24, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, [Pa.], L.S. 1p.Typed L.S. 1p. Sets date for talk on fossil sloth. For printed Paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 36-70.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 26, 1896; 11x8-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], Typed L.S. 1p., end. Letter of resignation as Curator.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Dec. 26, 1896; 9-1/4x5-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Agrees to hurry revision of his paper on "Exploration of ancient key dwellers' remains on the Gulf Coast of Florida." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Dec. 26, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, [Pa.], L.S. 1p. Concerns his talk on the fossil sloth. For printed talk, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 36-70.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, Dec. 26, 1896; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.] Typed L.S. 1p., end. Thanks for list of societies receiving the Transactions.
  - Report of the Secretaries on their meeting held to receive nominations for offices, Dec. 29, 1896; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Typed D. with MS. corrections, S.: George F[rederick] Barker, Patterson DuBois, Persifor Frazer. 1p. Contains transcript of Bache's letter of resignation as Curator. Carbon copy.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Dec. 29, 1896; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Horn, Katherine S.
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Report on Horn's health.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 29, 1896; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Munsell's, Joel, sons.
    Albany, N.Y., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Thanks for list of members.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Dec. 29, [1896]; 9-1/2x6; Greene, Wm. H. (William Houston), 1853-1918
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Nominates Brinton for Secretary.
  - Receipt ... to J. E. Humphrey, Dec. 29, 1896; United States Express Company.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Dec. 30, 1896; 10x7; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Finds fault with form of ballot for R.M. Bache.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Dec. 30, 1896; 8-1/4x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will ask him for information needed from the Secretaries.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, Dec. 30, 1896; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns list of members attending in 1896. Where is name of Charles C. Harrison?
  - Letter to E[benezer] D[on Carlos] Bassett, Phila., Dec. 31, 1896; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p. Copy. Enc. wanting. Returns letter with thanks. Discusses abolition of slavery and franchise problems in Philadelphia.
  - Note to the [A.P.S.], [1896]; 8x5, 2x3; Drown, Thomas Messinger, 1842-1904
    South Bethlehem, Pa., A.N.S. 1p. Printed label pinned to sheet. Change of address.
  - Receipt for Proceedings, no. 149, [1896]; 2-3/4x4-3/4; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Wallingford, Pa., D.S. with MS. addition. 1p., end. Change of address.
  - Letter to W[illia]m B[erryman] Scott, [1896]; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Copy. About Scott's MSS.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, 1896; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    [Phila.,]. A.L.S. 2p. Asks to postpone his talk on the fossilsloth. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 36-70.